Register of the Radu Irimescu Papers, 1918-1940
Hoover Institution Archives
Radu Irimescu Papers
1918-1940
75090
Irimescu, Radu
5 manuscript boxes, 1 album box, 11 envelopes (4.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, dispatches, memoranda, clippings, and photographs, relating to Romanian politics and foreign policy, and to the development of aviation in Romania.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1975.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Romania. Ministerul aerului si marinei.; Aeronautics--Romania.; Romania.; Romania--Foreign relations--United States.; Romania--History--1914-1944.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Foreign relations--Romania.; Statesmen--Romania.
Series Description
- Correspondence, 1931-1938, 1952. (Box No. 1-2.)
  Correspondence arranged alphabetically by last name of correspondent.
- Subject File, 1918-1940. (Box No. 2-4.)
  Correspondence, notes, memoranda, minutes of meetings, charts, lists, clippings, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject.
- Miscellany. (Box No. 5.)
  Clippings, calling cards, memorabilia, and miscellaneous printed matter, arranged as listed.
- Photographs., (837 prints / 5 albums / 1 envelopes (Box 75090 - 10.A-V)
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1931-1938, 1952
  - American Scantic Line w Polsce (Warsaw), 1934 (Box 1.)
  - Andrews, R. B., 1936
  - Anglo-Rumanian Society (Bucharest), 1937
  - Ausnit, Ma, 1936
  - Automobile Club of America (New York), 1935
  - Baicov, A., 1936
  - Balbo, General, n.d.
  - Bentin Amit, B., 1936
  - Bertram, S. R., 1936
  - Bibescu, D., 1934
  - Blank, Aristide, n.d.
  - Blum, Adalbert, n.d.
  - Boerescu, Neagu, 1933
  - Bolton, William, 1936
  - Bonescu, George, 1935
  - Boutry, Mr., 1936
  - Boxshall, E. G., 1936
  - Bradbury, Wilkinson and Company, Limited (England), 1933
  - Brebenariu, Gheorghe, 1936
  - Bristol Aeroplane Company, Limited, The (London), 1932-1933
  - Bulloch, M. A., 1933
  - Butculescu, N., 1935
  - Caranfil, N. G., 1933
  - Cercul de Sparturi Baneasa Country Club (Bucharest), 1935
  - Chrissoveloni Bank (Bucharest), 1935-1936
  - Chrissoveloni, Z. M., 1936
  - Consolidated Aircraft Corporation (New York), 1935
  - Corbin, A. O., 1936
  - Corfescu, Nicu, n.d.
  - Costinescu, Emil E., n.d.
  - Czapskyu, A. O., 1934
  - Danciulescu, Simion, 1935
  - Davenport, William S., 1932
  - Delavrancea, Cella, 1935
  - Denain, General, 1934
  - Detroyat, Michel, 1934-1935
  - Diaconescu, Nicolae, n.d.
  - Dombrowski, Colonel, 1936
  - Duca, Doanna, 1936
  - Finkelstein, Filippe, n.d.
  - Fischer, Leon, 1936
  - Fleischacker, R., 1936
  - France
    - Legation in Bucharest, n.d.
    - Minister of Aviation, 1933
  - Frye, Jack, 1936
  - Fulga, Fred, 1936
  - Ghitescu, Amedeu, 1933
  - Ghyka, M. C., 1973
  - Gudju, Captain, 1934
  - Hughes, John, 1935
  - Iliescu, Paul P., 1937
  - Industrieller Klub (Wein), 1935
  - International Standard Electric Corporation (London), 1933
  - Ionasiu, Titu, 1936
  - Irimescu, Henrietta, n.d.
  - King, Patrick, 1934
  - Lapedatu, I., 1933
  - MacDonald, A., 1934
  - Manolescu, A., 1935
  - Marcu, V., 1935
  - Mironescu, George, 1934
  - Molnar, Inginer L., 1936
  - Mosing, Ernest, 1935
  - Mounce, Gordon, 1936
  - Mutual Life Insurance Company of New York, 1932
  - Nicolaides, E. M., 1934
  - Niculescu, Gh., 1936
  - Niculescu, Lungu N., 1936
  - Odlum, Floyd, 1932-1935, 1952
  - Orezeanu, Tudor, 1935
  - Page, F. Handley, 1933
  - Park Lane Hotel (London), 1935
  - Pherichide, Irina, 1936
  - Popescu, Stefan, 1933
  - Popoviciu, Stefan, 1933
  - Popp, Mr., 1936-1937
  - Prefect, Mr., 1936
  - Radulescu, Savel, 1934
  - Rascanu, Iosif, 1937
  - Rayski, Ludomi, 1933, 1935
  - "Redeventa" (Bucharest), 1936
  - Revue Arcos (Brussels), 1936
  - Riaea, Niculescu, 1937
  - Romania, Legation in Washignton, D.C., 1936
  - Romanian Air Industry (Industria Aeronautic Romana), 1935
  - Romanian Commercial Bank, (Bucharest), 1935
  - "Romano Americana" (Bucharest), 1935
  - Rosenthal, L. C., 1936
  - Rumanian Naval League, 1937
  - Russian Legation in Bucharest, 1935-1936
  - Samsonovic, Nicolae, 1936
  - Schenker and Company (Bucharest), 1935-1936
  - Serban, Mihai, 1936
  - Smith, Wesley, 1934
  - Stefanescu-Radu, I., 1931
  - Stern, Otto, 1936
  - Tabacovici, Nicolae, 1936
  - Tanasoca, Nicolae A. & Brothers, 1936
  - Tarcauanu, Madame, 1936
  - Tatos, Vargolici, 1934, 1936
  - Teodoreanu, V., 1936-1937
  - Teodorescu, T., 1933
  - Thenen, S. L., 1934
  - Tillman, Lloyd, 1935
  - Titulescu, Nicolae, 1936
  - U.S. Ordnance Engineers, Incorporated, Chemical Warfare Munition (Cleveland, Ohio), 1936
  - Von Wiegand, Karl H., 1932-1933
  - "Vulcan" (Bucharest), 1937
  - Vulcanescu, Mr., 1936
  - Wadsworth, Mr., 1935
  - Warner, C. P., 1935 (Box 2.)
  - Works Development Company, Limited, The (Bucharest), 1934
  - Zakaria, Ion, 1936-1937
  - Miscellaneous
- SUBJECT FILE, 1918-1940
  - Airlines (general) (Box 2.)
  - Aviation
  - Bills, financial statements, receipts, etc.
  - Blank, Aristide, "Conversion of the Agricultural and Urban Debts" (in Rumanian), February 1933
  - Butculescu, N.
  - Certificates, introductory letters, etc.
  - Chrissoveloni Bank (Bucharest), 1933-1937
  - Condolences
  - Cot, Pierre
  - Donescu, Mr., transcript of the conference held on April 27, 1936, between Mr. Donescu and Mr. Deeus (in French)
  - Draft of a project to create a coffee monopoly (in Rumanina), undated
  - Electric Bond and Share Company (New York), Report to Stockholders, June 30, 1936
  - International Aeronautical Exposition (Paris), November 1932
  - Irving Trust Company (New York), 1932-1935
  - Italy, trip to, December 1937
  - Marie, Queen of Rumania, luncheon at Bankers Club (New York,) October 22, 1926
  - Marriage contract between Major M. Irimescu and Lucretia R. Popescu, 1889 (typewritten copy) (Box 3.)
  - Metropolitan Club (Bucharest)
  - Powell, Alice M., estate of 1950
  - Report on electrical energy used in Bucharest, 1932 (in French)
  - Royal maneuvres in 1934
  - Romania
    - Aviation
      - General, 1931-1937
      - Clippings, 1932-1934
      - Correspondence, 1932-1934
      - Commissary of Wheat
        - Correspondence, 1932-1935
        - Correspondence, 1933-1935
        - "Report of the Commissar for the Development of Wheat" (in Rumanian), October 9, 1933
      - Legation in London, 1937
      - Ministry of Air and Navy (Box 4.)
        - "Achievements of the Ministry of Air and Navy Since Its Inception until the Present" (in Rumanian), July 20, 1939
        - Rumanian Naval Service, 1936-1938
      - Ministry of National Defense, 1936-1938
      - Ministry of Public Works and Communications
        - "Personal Status of the P.C.A." (In Rumanian), October 29, 1936
        - "Rulings on the Status of the Personnel of the P.C.A." (in Rumanian), December 19, 1936
      - Navy, 1927, 1932, 1934, 1937-1938
  - Rumanian Air Industry (I.A.R. - Industria Aeronatica Romana), 1937-1938 (Box 5.)
  - Rumanian Royal Aeronautical Federation (Federatia Aeronautica Regala a Romaniei), 1933-1934, 1937
  - Society of British Aircraft Constructors (London), 1933
  - Yacht Club (Bucharest)
- MISCELLANY
  - Clippings (Box 5.)
  - Miscellaneous notes, printed matter, memorabilia, etc.
- Photographs. (Box 75090 - 10.A-V)
  - 113 photos depicting R. Irimescu's visit to Italy., 1937 (Folder fA)
  - SAME as fA. 69 photos (Folder fB)
  - 12 photos depicting R. Irimescu's visit to an Italian aircraft manufacturing plant., 1937 (Folder fC)
  - 23 photos of R. Irimescu inspecting German aircraft., 1937 (Folder fD)
  - 50 photos depicting R. Irrimescu's visit to Italy., 1937 (Folder fE)
  - 31 photos depicting R. Irimescu in various stages of his life. (Folder F)
  - 17 photos depicting R. Irimescu and his wife. (Folder G)
  - 10 photos of R. Irimescu with Queen Marie in New York., undated (Folder H)
  - 17 photos of the interior of the Rumanian Embassy quarters in Washington, D.C. (Folder I)
  - 102 photos depicting R. Irimescu, King Carol and others inspecting aircraft and manufacturing plants. (Folder J)
  - 47 photos depicting aircraft and including many aerial scenes (Folder K)
  - 99 photos depicting R. Irimescu, King Carol, and various statesmen, military officers, and domestic and foreign dignitaries at state, military and social functions. (Folder L)
  - 47 photos. SAME as L. (Folder M)
  - 89 photos depicting R. Irimescu, King Carol, and various statesmen, military officers, and domestic and foreign dignitaries at state, military and social functions. (Folder N)
  - 71 photos depicting King Carol with R. Irimescu and other various military, state and social functions. (Folder O)
  - 40 unidentified photos collected by R. Irimescu. (Folder P)